C.Karthik RajaFeatured Resume

Retail Sales Officer seeking roles in Sales, Marketing, Business Development, Channel Management, Brand Management, Product Promotion, Competitor Analysis, Trend Analysis, Key Account Management, B2B Marketing, Channel Sales, Retail Operations

Current Designation: Retail Sales Officer (Marketing)

Current Company: Saint Gobain India Pvt Ltd - (Glass Business)

Current Location: Chennai

Pref. Location: Chennai, Pondicherry, Cuddalore

Functional Area: Sales / BD

Role: Area Sales Manager

Industry: Construction/Engineering/Cement/Metals

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Total Experience: 9 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Notice Period: 2 Months

Highest Degree: MBA/PGDM [Marketing]

Key Skills: Retail Sales Officer, Area Sales Manager, Sales, Marketing, Business Development, Channel Management, Brand Management, Product Promotion, Competitor Analysis, Trend Analysis, Key Account Management, B2B Marketing, Channel Sales, Retail Operations

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

ID: 084b7a5f6f94106179Last Active: 18-Sep-20Last Modified: 18-Sep-20

Jump to SectionWork Experience | Education | IT Skills | Work Authorization

Summary

A competent professional with over 9 years of experience in Sales, Marketing, Business Development, Channel Management, Brand Management, Product Promotion, Competitor Analysis, Trend Analysis, Key Account Management, B2B Marketing, Channel Sales, Retail Operations and closes business deals and maintains extensive knowledge of current market conditions. Build long-term relationships with new and existing customers vast experience with branding and introducing new products. Superb understanding of business sense and strategies promote new products, and interact with new clients in order to develop sustained business for the organization.

Work Experience

Saint Gobain India Pvt Ltd - (Glass Business) as Retail Sales Officer (Marketing)

Aug 2014 to Till Date

Job Highlights:

Handled Retail Channels in 11 districts (Kanchipuram, Vellore, Dharmapuri, Krishnagiri, Thiruvannamalai, Villupuram, Cuddalore, Nagapattinam, Thanjavur, Thiruvarur, Pudukkottai) of Tamilnadu state and 1 district (Karaikal) in Pondicherry state.

Handling Retail Channels in Chennai market from January 2019.

Received South India's Best Retail Officer Award for the consecutive 2 times.

Kansai NEROLAC Paints Ltd as Territory Sales Supervisor (Marketing)

Aug 2012 to Jul 2014

Job Highlights:

Handled Retail Channels in Pondicherry, Villupuram district & Cuddalore district.

Placed 22 automatic Paint tinting machines and opened 40 new dealer accounts.

Opened South India's first Nerolac Impression Shopee Exclusive showroom in Cuddalore, with against cash billing of Rupees 15 lakhs material in a single day.

SNOWCEM Paints Pvt Ltd as SALES EXECUTIVE (Marketing)

Aug 2011 to Aug 2012

Job Highlights:

Handled Retail Channels in Cuddalore District and opened 28 new dealer accounts.

Achieved Thiruvannamalai District Court Project painting worth Rupees 10 lakhs by repeated follow up of Tamil Nadu's leading government contractor P.S.K Constructions.

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computer Science) from Annamalai University in 2009

PG: MBA/PGDM (Marketing) from BHARATHIYAR UNIVERSITY in 2011

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name Version Last Used Experience

WINDOWS 2000, XP, vista, 7

Microsoft Office